# Chiemela NDUKWE | Web Developer, I T Consultant & Analyst

Location: Abuja

Phone: (+234) 803 9572016

Email: <a href="mailto:chiemela@eliamtechnologies.com">chiemela@eliamtechnologies.com</a>

### **Professional Profile**

An accomplished IT Consultant & Analyst with a background in computer programming, web design & development, mobile development, computer networking & configuration across public and private sector organizations as well extensive infrastructure project experience.

With broad range of IT support experience coupled with a robust understanding of IT infrastructure and environments within large organizations, I have delivered support solutions that ensure optimal levels of IT service performance. With Microsoft certifications and a Diploma in Computer Science, I possess a deep technical knowledge across business systems including hardware, software, networking and change methodology.

### Core Skills

- JAVA, C#, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, HTML/CSS
- Web Design & Development
- Software & Hardware Troubleshooting
- · CMS expert in WordPress and Joomla
- · Networking & Configuration certified
- Hardware Maintenance & Upgrade Certified
- Mobile app development

- Server Performance Management
- Firewall and IT Security Management
- Cyber Security support
- On-site and Remote Support
- System Analysis and Design
- Database Management
- SEO

### **Career Summary**

Jun 2019 – Sep 2019

ECOWAS COMMISION, ANNEX II, ABUJA, NIGERIA Adhoc Staff

#### Outline

I worked as an adhoc staff for the Digitalization of all documents in ECOWAS PSS Project.

#### Key Responsibilities

- Sort out all documents according to projects
- Sort out all documents according to dates
- Scan all documents to save automatically to a designated folder on the network
- Lead the team and report to the consultant with recent updates on progress
- Login to the secure server and upload the scanned documents
- · Organize documents and files and upload them to the online server
- · Manage all the scanned files and documents
- Write a daily report on the work done for the day

Sep 2018 – June 2019 Intrans Advisory Services, Abuja, Nigeria Management & IT Director

#### Outline

Ensure smooth operation and good communication with partners, attend to all IT related issues.

#### Key Responsibilities

- Control over all online presence
- Look out for more partnership opportunities
- Report to the CEO on any potential partnership
- Report to the CEO concerning necessary payments that are not yet cleared
- Register and change the payment slips into actual receipt at AMAC
- Suggest the best web server to maintain a steady uptime with potential partners
- Manage the submission of credentials and CVs on company web site

## Jul 2018 – Sep 2018 Ebiku Investment Ltd, Abuja, Nigeria IT Director

#### Outline

Ensure all events are captured and used as adverts online, run a social media campaign to promote the product, build and manage the administrative web application to monitor the progress of sales.

#### Key Responsibilities

- Constantly report to the CEO on progress in the online marketing and road marketing
- Supervise major operations to ensure processes run smoothly
- Updated the basic coding used on the company website to a more secure scripting language (PHP)
- Suggest the best web server to run the web application
- Build an administrative web application

## Jan 2018 – April 2018 BICNORAS, Owerri, Nigeria Security systems analyst

#### Outline

Carried out various Security System Installation contracts with experts in Security Systems, this involves installation of CCTV systems, Intercoms, and Solar systems.

#### Key Responsibilities

- Suggest to clients the best security system to use depending on the analysis made
- Installation of CCTV for clients at their office, hotel and home
- Installation of intercom for in various hotels and offices
- Purchase and installation of Solar system with inverters

#### Aug 2016 – Dec 2017 Independent Contractor

#### Outline

I carried out jobs and contracts relating to programming, networking, analysis and design, hardware and software upgrade & maintenance, IT consulting

#### Key Responsibilities

- Started up a Bulk SMS business
- Started a social media campaign
- Built the very first E-Transcript System for a university (Seat of Wisdom Seminary School Philosophy Department) with C#
- Built online application for an NGO (Beyond Borders Voluntary Health Care Givers' Association)
- Supplied computer equipment and accessories to Mother of Good Counsel School and did all the necessary installations to make them run smoothly
- Built a Bulk SMS site for Seat of Wisdom Seminary School Philosophy Department
- Systems upgrade and maintenance of Seat of Wisdom Seminary School Philosophy department
- Offered bulk SMS services to numerous clients, marketed and sold numerous bulk SMS utility tools
- Offered private coaching services
- Offered technical support to logical programming problems to young programmers

## May 2015 – July 2016 E- Cert ICT, Owerri, Nigeria Consultant, Analyst & Coach

#### Outline

Consulting on computer programming, web design & development, system upgrade & maintenance, networking & configuration, providing analytic support and coaching.

#### Key Responsibilities

- Mapped out the coaching processes for the support analyst and other coaches
- Made suggestions on how their various social media platforms should be managed
- Organized the coaching scheme of work
- Built a Text Management & Phone number editor software in C#(C-Sharp) that manipulates and reorders phone numbers for E-Cert ICT bulk SMS website
- Coached clients on core Visual Basic.Net
- Coached clients on advanced troubleshooting
- Provided Hard Disk recovery services
- Part of all managerial meetings
- Ensured proper database management for clients
- Built responsive and interactive websites
- I give the right specifications and the brand of computer or equipment to buy for clients
- Supply and installation of computers to schools and offices, performed hardware installations including configuring
- Facilitate effective solutions that ensured systems worked at optimal levels

## Jan 2015 – April 2015 Mobile Technologies Network Services, Owerri, Nigeria Interim Manager

#### Outline

Overseeing other employees, controlling the operations of the firm, directing and supervising other employees and demanding daily reports from the staffs

#### Key Responsibilities

- Overseeing all web designs
- Directing and making corrections to web designs templates
- Have access to all VPN accounts
- Purchase of VPN accounts from vendor
- Management of company finances
- Managing access and assigning appropriate permissions to ensure security remains optimal
- Make new clients and retain the old clients
- Manage the various social media platforms
- Initiate more online campaigns to promote the firm
- Oversee and monitor firm change methodology
- Assign coaches to clients appropriately
- Oversee the System Upgrade & Maintenance process
- Ensure that backups were carried out and that all data are secure
- Performed customer service follow-ups to ensure that IT issues had been resolved to their satisfaction
- · Highlighted trends and recurring support issues and advised helpdesk supervisor of problems

## Nov 2012 – Dec 2014 Mobile Technologies Network Services, Owerri, Nigeria IT Helpdesk Analyst & Coach

#### Outline

Reporting to the manager, providing technical and coaching support to clients at our office base in Imo State and supervising ongoing firm operational projects.

#### Key Responsibilities

- · Identify client needs and provide suitable solution and advice
- Bill the client according to the package the training package they chose
- Provide Software upgrade and maintenance for clients both PC and Mobile
- Provide Hard Drive recovery and error fixing using Windows Command Line
- Recover lost files due to virus attacks with Ubuntu OS and re-install windows
- Formatting of PCs to Windows 10 and fixing screen resolution problems that occurs afterwards
- Dismantling and dusting of Desktop and laptop motherboard, reassembling after being treated
- Provide client with VPN services
- Providing social media insights
- Designing of website templates for the firm based on Joomla and WordPress
- Coach clients on a 3 months intensive class on bulk SMS business
- Coach clients on a 3 months intensive class on web designing
- Conducted 2 seminars for the firm on web designing
- Conducted 3 seminars for the firm on digital marketing
- Ensure that everything necessary to run the office is fully operational
- iPhone and Android phone unlocking support to clients
- I purchase and supply computer equipment and accessories if the one we have is unfixable

### Education, Vocational Qualifications & Training

- Google Android Developer Associate certification Ongoing
- · Elements of AI certification Ongoing
- Fundamentals of digital marketing Ongoing
- Make Sure Customers Find You Online Passed (2020)
- Create Your Business Profile on Google certificate Passed (2020)
- HND certificate Passed (2015 2017)
- Cyber Security 2 Passed (2017)
- Cyber Security 1 Passed (2016)
- OND certificate Passed (2012 2014)
- Computer Networking and configuration Passed (2013)
- Basic Hardware upgrade and Maintenance Passed (2013)
- Basic Computer Operations Passed (2012)

### Technical Knowledge

- Computer Programming
- Cisco Systems
- Computer upgrade & maintenance
- Windows Environment
- Cyber Security
- · Making Customers Find You Online

- System hardware & Installation
- Desktop/Laptops
- Network Installation & Configuration
- Printers
- System performance
- Creating a Business Profile Online

#### Other Oualities

- I enjoy Programming, Logical problems, Quantitative reasoning, and Statistics.
- Functioned as the sanitary prefect in my primary six because of my neatness and won the bestbehaved male students of the year.
- Functioned as the school computer prefect and also as the class prefect in the secondary school.
- During my days at higher institution I was one of the elite programmers who were called by the school to develop the very first registration and voting system for the school.
- I tutored my fellow course mates on programming, web designing, database management, and computer maintenance while I was still in high institution.
- I have volunteered for various health outreach programs with the aim of providing health care to the less privileged and create awareness on Yellow fever, Breast cancer, Hepatitis.
- I am an athlete I like to keep fit mentally and physically plus it helps me relax.